Sheppard呼叫Atlantis
Atlantis,this is sheppard.
我正在接近星门
I'm on approach to the gate.
收到
Acknowledged.
自从我到飞马系以来 我在 嗯...
Since I've been in pegasus,I have set up,like,what,
好几个星球上建立了研究站
half a dozen research stations on various planets?
可我从没有见过你主动要去补给的
And I don't remember you ever volunteering to run a resupply mission to any of them.
我可是个大忙人 Rodney
I'm a busy man, Rodney.
我只是刚好有点时间
I just happen to have a little free time.
而Mackenzie博士碰巧又在研究
一个住在热带天堂里的原始部落
And Dr.Mackenzie just happens to be studying a primitive tribe that lives in a tropical paradise,
他怎么说的来着?
and has-- how did he put it?
未谙羞耻为何物?
Little or no social inhibitions?
他们很友好
Well,they were very friendly.
怎么搞的?
What the hell?
怎么了?
What is it?
我想刚刚有人打了我一枪
I think somebody just took a shot at me.
有敌情 他们正在快速接近
I've got contact.They're closing fast.
是Wraith吗?
Was it wraith?
应该不是 但...
I don't think so,but--
不管他们拿什么打我的
那东西把我的系统短路了
Whatever they're shooting me with just shorted my systems.
我没法启动武器
I can't get weapons online.
你能回到星门吗?
Can you make it back to the gate?
Sheppard!
Rodney?
Mckay?
Stargate Atlantis
第4季 第5集
Season 4 Episode 05
旅行者
Travelers
船很不错
Nice ship.
就是有点...
A little bit of a...
有点需要修修了 但是很有潜质
(fixer-upper只翻修以后还有价值的房子)
Little bit of a fixer-upper,but I can see the potential.
我不是说大规模的
I'm not talking about anything drastic,you know.
也许只要刷刷漆
放两个抱枕作装饰
Maybe just a paint job,some throw pillows.
我想你们不打算告诉我
这是怎么回事吧?
Look,I don't suppose you want to tell me what's going on here?
下面是这样的
Here's how we're going to do this.
我问 你答
I'm going to ask you questions,and you're going to give me answers.
够简单了吧?
Is that simple enough for you?
嗯
Sure.
你是谁? 你从哪来?
你如何得到你的飞船的?
Who are you,where are you from,and where did you get your ship?
真是巧 我也要问一样的问题
See,that's a funny coincidence,because I was going to ask you the same exact questions.
关键是我的手没有被绑在后面
[Punch] The difference is I'm not the one whose hands are tied behind his back.
那么 我再问一遍 你是谁?
你从哪来?你如何得到你的飞船的?
So,again,who are you,where are you from,and where did you get your ship?
出什么事了?
What happened?
我不太确定
I'm not entirely sure.
看上去 Sheppard的Jumper
在到达星门之前被攻击了
Looks like Sheppard's jumper was attacked before he reaches the space gate.
谁攻击的?
By who?
那个星球上的人
还在刀耕火种的时代
Well,the people on the planet aren't much past mud huts and blow darts,
所以我们可以假定不是他们
so we can assume they had nothing to do with it.
就在我们失去联系以后
星门附近有一个和打开超空间窗口
Just after we lost contact,there was a short burst of radiation in the vicinity of the gate,
很一致的短暂辐射爆发
consistent with the opening of a hyperspace window.
是Wraith吗?
Wraith?
Sheppard说不是
Sheppard didn't seem to think so,
从Jumper上接收的一点
传感器数据可以证实这一点
and what little sensor data we've been able to pick up from the jumper seems to confirm it.
能量特征完全不同
The energy signature's all wrong.
而且也和古人的不一样
也就是排除了复制者
It's inconsistent with ancient technology as well,which pretty much rules out the replicators.
我们知道的本星系的其他种族
都没有超空间技术
We know of no other peoples in this galaxy that possess hyperspace technology.
当然 没有人能在被洗劫的时候
达到那么高级的水平
Of course not.No one reaches anywhere near that level of advancement without being culled.
那么是谁呢?
So then who was it?
我可以一整天都干这个
I could do this all day.
你的关节最后会酸的
Oh,your knuckles'll get sore eventually.
他有说什么吗?
Has he said anything?
只有他的名字
Only his name.
Reed Richards
(神奇四侠主角之一)
Reed richards.
他叫Sheppard
His name is sheppard.
我们截获了他最后的无线电通讯
We intercepted part of his last radio transmission.
我还不知道你的名字呢
I didn't catch your name.
你可以叫我Larrin
You can call me larrin.
你真的应该合作
You really should cooperate.
如果伤害太大就可惜了
It would be a shame to have to do too much damage.
我同意
I agree.
如果你们告诉我你们是谁
和你们的意图
Maybe if you guys tell me who you are and what you want,
我们可以达成协议
we could work out some kind of a deal.
那就不要吊起我的胃口
然后扫我的兴
Well,don't get my hopes up and then disappoint me.
和他说说上一个让我失望的人
后来怎么了
Tell him what happened to the last man that disappointed me.
我们不知道
We don't know.
从没找到他的尸体
We never found his body.
我猜你(Larrin)把他抛到了宇宙里
We assumed you blew him out into space.
我懂了
I get it.
好的
Good.
带上他
Bring him.
起来
Get up.
另一种折磨方式?
Another form of torture?
当你像我们一样长时间呆在宇宙里
When you spend as much time in space as we do,
你就很难吃到新鲜食物
you don't get a lot of fresh food.
多长时间?
How much time are we talking about?
这应该是一个对话 是吧?
This is a conversation,right?
双向的
A two-way street?
这就是我们的家
This is our home.
这艘飞船?
This ship?
还有其他类似的飞船
And others like it.
我们是旅行者
We're travelers.
你们一直住在宇宙空间
You live in space all the time.
在需要时我们才降落
比如 补给和交易时
We land on planets when we need to,for supplies,trade.
其他时候 我们保持移动
The rest of the time,we keep moving.
躲避Wraith吗?
From the wraith?
也许开始时是的
That may have been how it started,
但现在这就是我们的生活
but now it's just who we are.
没有别的意思 Larrin
Well,no offense,larrin.
但这听上去一点都不像生活
It doesn't sound like much of a life.
做群居动物也不是生活
Being a herd animal isn't much of a life.
而且 这些食物包含了必须的营养
Besides,the food has all the nutrients required.
听上去有点唐突
但是这东西味道不太好
Well,as tempting as that sounds,my jaw's a little sore right now.
事情并不总是这样
Things like that are necessary from time to time.
虽然这不是获取信息
最有效的方式
Although it's not the most efficient way of getting information,
但这有助于人理解...
it does help people to understand...
他们的处境
their situation.
我的处境取决于你的仁慈
My situation being completely at your mercy.
没错
Exactly.
不管怎样 我了解你超过你的想象
Anyway,I know more about you than you think.
真的?
Really?
比如说 我知道你带有
可以操作Lantian科技的基因
For instance,I know that you carry the gene required to operate lantian technology.
我有什么?
I've got the what?
Sheppard 我知道你有你的秘密
Look,sheppard,I know you have your secrets,
如果你好好表现
我能让你保留一些
and if you stay on my good side,I may even let you keep a few of them.
但是如果你继续装蒜
However,if you continue to play ignorant with me,
我真的会把你抛到太空中去
I really will jettison you out into space.
一段时间以来我们听到传言说
一群新的人类到达了这个星系
For some time now,we've been hearing rumors about a new group of humans in the galaxy
他们用古人的技术和Wraith开战
using the technology of the ancestors to do battle with the wraith.
所以我们在一些空间星门附近
设置了间谍卫星网络
So we set up a network of spy satellites around dozens of worlds with space gates,
希望能有收获
hoping for an encounter.
终于我们成功了
Eventually we got lucky.
然后在我们第一次见面的时候
你攻击了我并解除了我船上的武器
And in the first meeting between our people,you attack me and disarm my ship.
你要使用星门
我不能允许
You were going through the gate,and I couldn't let that happen.
我们对任何能操作Lantian技术
的人都有特别的兴趣
You see,anyone capable of operating lantian technology is of particular interest to us.
所以你们取了我的血样
That's why you took a sample of my blood.
我们正在做一个控制界面适配器
它需要小量的遗传物质来工作
We're working on a control interface adapter that requires a small amount of necessary genetic material.
我么需要用你的血液做测试
We needed your blood to test it.
我猜你们进行的不是很顺利
I'm going to guess it didn't go so well.
为什么这么说?
Why would you say that?
如果不是的话
你们就不需要我了
Then you wouldn't have any use for me anymore.
不要低估你自己
Don't underestimate yourself.
你的用处可大着呢
There's all kinds of useful things you could do for me.
指挥官 我们快要到达坐标
Commander,we're approaching the coordinates.
明白
Understood.
跳出超空间
Take us out of hyperspace.
你是对的
Of course you're right.
控制界面还没有完成
The interface isn't fully operational yet.
跟我来
Come with me.
这是Nevik 我的首席科学官
Nevik,my chief science officer,
他坚持我们能更好的完善这个界面
insists that we have a much better chance of perfecting the interface
如果我们能对已经启动的
if we reverse-engineer it using lantian technology
Lantian科技进行反向工程
that's already been initialized.
我连反向工程是什么都不知道
I don't even know what reverse engineering is.
哦 你们想用我的飞船
Oh,you want to use my ship.
不是
Not exactly.
嘿
Hey!
启动护盾
Activate the force shield.
Sheppard 你能听见吗?
Sheppard,can you hear me?
你想告诉我你在做什么吗?
You mind telling me what you're doing?
和你做笔交易
Offering you a deal.
打开机舱[??BSG里怎么翻的??]门
Open the hanger bay doors.
这可不对
This is just not right.
别担心
Don't worry.
只要护盾不出故障你就没有危险
You're safe as long as the force shield doesn't malfunction,and that almost never happens.
你为什么要这样做?
Why are you doing this?
你想知道为什么?
You wanted to know what this is all about.
向下看看
Look beneath you.
我猜你认得这个技术
I'm assuming you recognize the technology.
那是一个Latian战舰
It's a lantian battleship.
它已经休眠了几千年了
It's been dormant for thousands of years,
而你要帮我让它工作起来
and you're going to help me get it operational again.
你们没有想过他们弃船
肯定是有充分理由的?
Has it occurred to you people they might have abandoned the ship for a good reason in the first place?
我们知道原因
We know the reason.
我们访问了日志
We were able to access the ship's logs.
他们被Wraith攻击了
They were attacked by the wraith.
他们失去了通讯系统
并且护盾正在减弱
They lost communication,and the shields were failing.
引擎也受到损伤
但是他们逃入了超空间
The engines were damaged as well,but they managed to escape into hyperspace.
然后他们发现他们的主推进器
在发出致命的辐射
Then they realized that their main drive was giving off deadly radiation.
他们被迫弃船
They were forced to abandon ship.
他们想回来修复
但是从来没有机会
They intended to return and effect repairs,but never got the chance.
从那以后这艘船就以一个200年的
椭圆轨道围绕附近的一个矮星旋转
The ship's been drifting in a 200-year elliptical orbit around a nearby dwarf star ever since.
那么 它从没被修复
So it's never been fixed.
不是
No.
我不想明说...
I hate to point out the obvious,
但是我帮你的一个条件是
你不杀我
but one of the reasons I agreed to help you was so that you wouldn't kill me.
如果我要死在辐射中...
If I'm going to die of radiation anyway--
别担心
Don't worry.
我们设立了护盾发生器
以保护关键的区域
We've set up shield emitters to protect key areas of the ship,
而且我们有辐射探测器
and we've all got radiation detectors.
带他到舰桥
Take him to the bridge.
从次光速推进器开始
Start with sub-light propulsion.
我去检查发生器
I'll go check the emitters.
我可以弄一个吗?
Don't think I could get one of those,too,do you?
这里
Here.
这艘船可有一万年历史了
You know,this ship is 10,000 years old.
我只是说如果它不工作
不是我的错
I'm just saying,for the record,if it doesn't work,it's not my fault.
你做就好了
Just get on with it.
太神奇了
Amazing.
我试验了两个月
都没能启动这些系统
I've been trying for two months to activate these systems.
我要调整界面适应神经输入
I need to calibrate the interface for neural input.
你可以从前进开始
Why don't you start by moving the ship forward?
你确定?
You sure about that?
我们就是为这个来的
That's why we're here.
你开飞船 我记录输入
然后复制它们
You fly the ship,and I record the inputs so I can replicate them.
- 好的 但是...
- 够了
-Okay,but--
-enough.
该死的 快开
Fly the damn ship.
好的
Right.
我刚才想说 你说"从前进开始"
I was just going to say,you said "start by moving the ship forward,
但你应该说 "先启动惯性消除"
" when you should have said,"start by initializing the inertial dampeners.
等一下!
" Wait!
我朋友有一把一模一样的枪
I have a friend who's got a gun just like this.
我终于知道他从哪弄来的了
I always wondered where he got it.
我会杀了你的
I'm going to kill you.
Silas 发生了什么?
Silas,what happened?
Nevik上面怎么了?
[Groans] Nevik,what's going on up there?
对不起 你的人现在没法说话
Sorry,your people aren't available right now.
Sheppard 你在做什么?
Sheppard,what are you doing?
你叫我开飞船 我正在开飞船
You said fly the ship,and I'm flying the ship.
我们说好了的
We had a deal.
我准备让你走以换取你的帮助
I was prepared to let you go in exchange for your help.
抱歉 我还没相信过绑架并折磨我
I'm sorry,I've never been able to trust anyone who kidnaps me
还威胁要把扔到宇宙中的人
and tortures me and threatens to blow me into space.
我们一无所获
We've got nothing.
下面没有残骸 也没有发射器信号
There's no wreckage,no transponder signal.
如果他在下面
我们现在就该找到他了
If he was down there,we would have found him by now.
那么他在哪?
Then where is he?
他不在轨道上 也不在星球上
He's not in orbit,and he's not on the planet,
那么唯一逻辑的假设是
攻击他的人在跳跃前把他带上了船
so the only logical assumption is that whoever attacked him must have brought him onboard before they jumped into hyperspace.
那么下一步怎么办?
So,what's the next step?
没有下一步
There is no next step.
我们没有办法追踪他
Look,we have no way of tracing him.
他现在可能在任何地方
He could be anywhere in the galaxy by now.
很抱歉但是有时候我们无能为力
I'm sorry,but sometimes there is just nothing we can do.
Sheppard 我要你让飞船跳出超空间
Sheppard,I want you to drop this ship out of hyperspace.
我不会的
I don't think so.
听我说
Listen to me.
我关闭了保护你所在区域
的护盾发生器
I've shut off the shield emitters protecting your areas of the ship.
现在舰桥充满了辐射
Right now,the bridge is being flooded with radiation.
你在虚张声势
You're bluffing.
你不会牺牲你自己的人
You'd never sacrifice your own people.
听着 我不想杀你
Look,I don't want to kill you,
但是如果你不交出飞船的控制权
我别无选择
but if you don't turn over the controls of this ship,I'll have no choice.
你很令我惊讶 Sheppard
You surprise me,sheppard.
只要我没有让你失望
Well,as long as I didn't disappoint you.
没有 我知道你会反抗
Oh,no,I knew you'd make some sort of a move.
只是我没想到会是这么..
I just wasn't expecting anything quite so...
聪明? 创新?
Clever? Creative?
鲁莽
Reckless.
你有可能把我们都害死
包括你自己
You could have killed all of us,including yourself.
我有一次把F16加速到16g
而没有昏过去
I once pulled 11 gs in an f-16 without passing out.
我知道我有把握
I figured I had a shot.
看来 我低估了你
Well,I underestimated you.
我也这么觉得
I feel the same way.
[???]
I mean,you've got the whole tough-as-nails routine down pat,
但是把自己的人
暴露在致命的辐射中...
but exposing your own people to killer radiation...
只有很特别的女人才会 不是吗?
it takes a special kind of lady to do that,doesn't it?
Larrin
Larrin...
事情不太好
it's not good.
他关闭了推进和导航系统
He shut down the propulsion and navigation system before he turned over the bridge.
当然了
Of course he did.
你有收集到足够的数据
来完成控制界面吗?
Did you collect enough data to finish the control interface?
我不知道 也许吧
I don't know.Maybe.
Nevik 如果你做不成
我们就被困在这了
Nevik,if you can't do this,we're stranded.
他怎么办?
What about him?
他不能再接近舰桥
He's not going anywhere near that bridge again.
不能信任他
He can't be trusted.
不过我们不能启动系统
他会和我们一起死在这
If we can't bring the system back online,he'll die out here like the rest of us.
问题是
That's the problem.
他看上去像是准备死的人吗?
Does he look like a man who thinks he's going to die?
检查次空间通讯阵列
Check the subspace communications array.
古人在战争中失去了通讯系统
The ancients lost the communications in the battle with the wraith.
它从没被修复
The system was never repaired.
检查一下
Check it.
怎么了?
What have you got?
记得我说过我们无能为力吗?
Ah,remember how I said sometimes there's nothing we can do?
我是对的 只是这次不适用
I was right about that,only it turns out this is not one of those times.
你找到他了?
You found him?
实际上是他找到我们了 听
Hmm,more like he found us.Listen to this.
这是次空间的声音
That is the sound of subspace.
它大部分是由多种辐射
造成的随机噪声
Now,it's mostly just random noise generated by various forms of radiation,
但是万能的古人
but the ancients,in their infinite wisdom,
编写了一个程序来检测人造样式
created a program that could sniff out artificial patterns.
这无疑是它们远距探测
高级生命形态的方式
It's no doubt a long-range means of detecting advanced life-forms,
有点像我们的SETI程序
(通过分布式计算寻找外星通讯)
kind of like our seti program,
只是古人的更强大
因为他们使用次空间
only much more powerful because it operates through subspace.
不管怎样 程序检测到了这个
Anyway,it picked up this.
这是什么?
What is it?
是Sheppard
That's sheppard.
我不知道为什么
他没发送一个普通消息
I do not know why he didn't just send a regular message.
也许他用的是一个坏的发送机
Maybe he was dealing with a damaged transmitter,
或者他想在不被发现的情况下
发出信息 但这肯定是他
or maybe he was trying to communicate without being detected,but it's definitely him.
你怎么知道?
How do you know it's him?
这是摩尔电码
It's morse code.
SOS
S.O.S.
怎么了?
What's happening?
这又是为了什么?
What was that for?
你知道你干了什么吗?
You realize what you've done?
我什么都没做
I didn't do anything.
不要再打了!
Stop that!
你停止说谎 我就停
I'll stop when you stop lying.
你修改了坏的通讯阵列
来发送信息 是不是?
You adapted the damaged communications array to send out a signal,didn't you?
是的
Yes.
你说过...
You said...
你会停止打我的!
you'd stop that!
没错
You're right.
也许该用枪打你
Maybe I'll just shoot you.
好吧
All right.
你没有觉得你反映过度了吗?
Don't you think you're overreacting a little?
你尝试着广播我们的位置是吗?
You were trying to broadcast our location?
知道怎么样了吗? 你成功了
Guess what?It worked.
有一艘船正在靠近
只是不是你想要的那一艘
There's a ship approaching,only I don't think it's the one you were hoping for.
你什么意思?
What do you mean?
来的是Wraith!
It's the wraith!
Wraith的飞船在找我们
The wraith ship is firing on us.
护盾在工作吗?
Do we have shields?
是的 但是只有20%
Affirmative,but they're only at 20%.
我们撑不了多久
We can't take this for very long.
如果你们要度过这个难关
你们需要我的帮助
If you want to get out of this alive,you're going to need my help.
我知道我们不信任对方 但是...
Now,I realize that you and I don't exactly trust each other,but...
但是如果Wraith要炸掉这艘船
那也没什么关系了 不是吗?
that's not going to make much difference if the wraith blow the ship up,is it?
你有什么想法?
What do you got in mind?
你可以先还击
Well,you can start by shooting back.
对
Right.
武器控制平台在走廊尽头
The weapons control platform is down that corridor.
我要回到舰桥去
I'm heading back to the bridge.
让护盾支撑的越久越好
Keep the shields up as long as you can.
太好了
Great.
小意思
Piece of cake.
护盾失效了
Shields are down.
你能多分配一点能源吗?
Can't you reroute any more power?
我无能为力
There's nothing I can do.
Silas Nevik 怎么回事?
Silas,nevik,what happened?
你们听见吗?
Do you read me?
Larrin
Larrin...
我是Sheppard
it's sheppard.
我没有给你通讯器
I didn't give you a communicator.
我启动了飞船的内部对讲系统
发生了什么事?
I activated the ship's intercom.What happened?
我不知道 飞船前部被封锁了
I don't know.The forward section's been sealed off.
你的人怎么样?
What about your people?
他们没有回应
They're not responding.
好消息是 Wraith的飞船被摧毁了
Good news is,the wraith ship's been destroyed.
你呆在那 我来找你
Stay where you are.I'm coming to you.
Sheppard 你在哪?
Sheppard,where are you?
辅助控制室
Auxiliary control room.
Sheppard?
Sheppard...
很抱歉
sorry about this.
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
目前为止 能做的不多
For the moment,not much.
超空间引擎离线了
Hyperdrive seems to be offline.
什么?
What?
有多严重?
How bad is it?
我不是这方面的专家
Well,it's not exactly my area of expertise,
但是如果我看得没错
but if I'm reading this thing right,
引擎本身没有受损
the drive itself is undamaged.
也许只是控制系统短路了
Probably just a short in the control system.
我们可以简单地用旁路来解决
Then we can take care of it through a simple bypass.
放我出去 我应该可以修好它
Just let me out,and I should be able to fix it.
我可不会
I don't think so.
我们现在是活靶子 Sheppard!
We're a floating target out here,sheppard!
没事 放心
All right,take it easy.
我已经把发信器关掉了
I shut the transmitter off.
我的人应该已经收到信息了
My people should've got the message by now.
你没有理由假定Wraith飞船
没有广播我们的位置
There is no reason to assume that wraith ship didn't broadcast our position.
也没有理由假定它们这么做了
Well,there's no reason to assume they did.
听我说 Sheppard
Listen to me,sheppard.
我的一生都花在超空间引擎上
I've spent my entire life around hyperdrive systems.
我知道该怎么修
I know what I'm doing.
我从没说过我不相信你
I never said I didn't believe you.
别担心
Don't worry.
我的人会来的
My people will be here.
Sheppard的广播是从
这个星系附近来的
Sheppard was broadcasting from somewhere in the vicinity of this system.
传感器没有收到任何东西
Well,sensors aren't picking up anything.
让我看看能不能把范围扩大一点
Let me see if I can expand the range a little.
那里
There.
那是什么?
What is it?
也许是一艘船
Could be a ship.
他们太远了 没法获取准确的读数
但是那肯定使他们
They're still too far out to get any detailed readings,but that's got to be them.
以最大亚光速多久能到那?
How long to get there at maximum sublight?
5小时
It's five hours.
Lorne呼叫所有Jumper
This is Lorne to all jumpers.
我正在把发送坐标给你们
I'm sending you some coordinates.
以最大亚光速前往目标
Proceed to target at maximum sublight.
Larrin你在做什么?
Larrin,what are you doing?
听着 我的人来了以后
他们会修好超空间引擎
Look,once my people get here and get the hyperdrive back online,
然后我们会把你送到最近的星门
we'll drop you off at the nearest gate.
我保证
You have my word.
还不够好
Not good enough.
什么? 我的保证还是我的条件?
What,my word or my deal?
两个都不好
How about both?
你是绑架我的人 记得吗?
You're the one who kidnapped me,remember?
但是我需要这艘船
Because I need this ship.
嗯
there.
我已经在帮你了
I did you a favor.
Sheppard...
听我说
listen to me.
我们的舰队很老了
Our fleet is old.
我们本有资源建造新船
但是现在没有了
There was a time when we had the resources to build new ships,but now we don'T.
如果我们损失了一艘 就是一艘
When we lose one,it's gone for good,
尽管人口控制已经很严格了
and despite strict population controls,
我们还是没有足够的地方
there just isn't enough room for all of us anymore.
我们已经被迫
将一些人遗弃在地面上
We've been forced to abandon some of our own people on the ground.
(地面上的人)他们不比
这个星系里的其他人活的差
Well,they're no worse off than the rest of the people in this galaxy.
那好
Fine.
我们还是用硬方法解决吧
We'll do this the hard way.
Larrin 你在做什么?
Larrin,what are you doing?
Sheppard 你真把我给惹毛了
Sheppard,you are really starting to annoy me!
好好坐着就好 很快就会结束的
Just sit tight.It'll be over soon enough.
Silas Nevil 回答
Silas,nevik,come in.
Silas 收到吗?
Silas,do you read me?
放弃吧 他们已经死了
Give it up.They're gone.
你不能确定
You don't know that.
我不能 但是我可以查出来
No,but I can find out.
看上去飞船前部没人生还
Looks like there's no one alive in the forward section.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
Larrin 你到哪去?
Larrin,where are you going?
在这艘船上你到哪 我都能跟踪你
I can track you anywhere on this ship.
你躲不过我的
You can't hide from me.
Larrin 停下
Larrin,stop.
我在你正前方收到了生命信号
I'm picking up another life-sign directly in front of you.
Silas
Silas...
不可能的
it's impossible.
他不可能活着离开那个区域
There's no way he got out of that section alive.
你没事吧?
You all right?
我没事
I'm fine.
它袭击了我
He just caught me off guard.
它们肯定是用Darts
从他们的飞船上逃出来的
They must've escaped in the darts before their ship was destroyed.
我们的机舱有加压
We left the hangar bay pressurized.
它们径直飞进来了
They flew right in.
它们?
They?
没错 还有3个
Yeah,there's three more.
我们可以用这个跟踪它们
We can track them with this.
你是从哪找到的?
Where did you get that?
辅助控制室
Auxiliary control room.
你得知道到什么地方找 快来
You got to know where to look.Come on.
我来拿他的枪
I'll get his weapon.
很顽强的小混蛋 不是吗?
Tenacious little bastards,aren't they?
我猜这个你没有多余的了
I don't suppose you have any more of these.
恐怕没有了
我想这个也不会有什么用
I'm afraid not,and I don't think this is going to be much good either.
停
Hold up.
这边来了一个
We got one coming this way.
现在怎么办?
What now?
等一下 Sheppard 你在干什么?
Wait,no,sheppard-- what are you doing?
哦 真是好点子
What-- oh,brilliant plan.
让我们... 啊
Get us-- ow!
另外两个也来了
There's the other two.
什么 它们在开会吗?
What,are they having a board meeting?
没用的 我已经尽全力
加强传感器了
It's no use.I've done all I can to boost the sensors.
他们还是太远了
They're still too far out.
那么我们不知道
我们要对付的是什么
So we have no idea what we're dealing with.
他们为什么在太阳系边缘
那么远的地方?
Why would they be so far out on the edge of the solar system?
我觉得这个星系不会
正巧有一个星门
I don't think it's a coincidence that this system has a space gate.
他们可能是在前往星门时
跳出超空间太早了
They were probably headed for it when they dropped out of hyperspace too early.
为什么呢?
Well,why would they do that?
我怎么知道?
how should I know?
我们连他们是谁都不知道
We don't even know who they are,remember?
有什么区别呢?
Does it make a difference?
即使那是一个母舰舰队
我们也会尝试把他救出来
Even if it was a fleet of hive ships,would it stop us from trying to get him back?
不会
No.
如果你合作的 这一切都不会发生
You know,none of this would have ever happened if you would have just cooperated.
你现在就应该到家了
You'd be home by now,
而我会给我的人民带回一艘飞船
and I'd be headed back to my people with a ship
一艘能容纳上千男女老少的飞船
that could house a thousand men,women,and children.
如果首先像我求助
而不是攻击我的话...
Well,if you had asked for my help in the first place instead of attacking me--
我们不能冒这个险
we couldn't risk it.
什么险?
Risk what?
你可能会说不
You might have said no.
他们走了
They're leaving.
等一下
Hold up.
我们有麻烦了
We got a problem.
他们在我们和控制室之间
They're between us and the control room.
我们应该可以找条路绕过去
We should be able to find a way around.
时间不够了
我们不能让它们先到
There isn't enough time.We can't risk them finding it first.
有什么关系呢? 他们又不能开船
What does it matter?It's not like they can fly the ship.
Sheppard...
你有把控制器关掉 是吧?
you did shut down the controls,right?
- Sheppard...
- 我没有时间...
-Sheppard--
-there wasn't enough time.
如果他们在我们之前到达控制室
If they find that control room before we do,
他们不仅能开这艘船
they'll not only be able to fly the ship,
而且还可以
用内部传感器追踪我们
but they're going to be able to track us using the internal sensors.
相信我 我知道 还有
Believe me,I know,and by the way,
我是要去救你的命
I was busy saving your life at the time.
我的生命会有危险
The only reason my life was in danger in the first place is
是因为你把我们的位置
广播到了半个星系
because you decided to broadcast our position to half the galaxy.
你是想吵这个
还是想做一些实际行动?
Do you want to argue about this,or do you want to do something about it?
好吧
Fine.
有什么选择?
What are the options?
我们没法去控制室 也没有武器
Well,we're cut off from the control room,and we have no weapons.
不尽然 我们可以用那把椅子
That's not true.We have the chair.
我觉得Drone对
船中的Wraith不会有什么用
I don't think drones are going to do any good with a bunch of wraith in the middle of the ship.
如果他们不在船中间呢?
What if they weren't in the middle?
正经一点
Get serious.
你有更好的办法吗?
You got a better idea?
好吧
All right.
我就位了
I'm in position.
等待我的信号
Wait for my signal.
你确定你要这么做?
You sure you want to go through with this?
如果你没有成功
我会有负罪感的
I mean,if you don't make it,I'm going to feel responsible,
我真的不需要这个负罪感
and,well,I really don't need the guilt.
只要你不放得太早
我就不会有事
I'll be fine as long as you don't shoot too early.
我肯定你不是第一次
听一个女人说这个话
I'm sure it's not the first time you've heard that from a woman.
正好相反 我可以忍耐
On the other hand,I might be able to live with it.
我看到它们了
I got 'em.
来了
Here we go.
Sheppard 现在发射
Sheppard,now!
Larrin 回话
Larrin,come in.
Larrin?
在我吸光你的生命之前
and now,before I take the rest of your life,
你要回答我一个问题
you will answer my questions.
你们还有几个人在船上?
How many more of your people are on this ship?
我可以不杀你
也可以让你痛快的死去
I do not have to kill you,nor do I have to leave you like this.
所以你最好合作
It would be better if you cooperated.
这是你最后的机会
This is your last chance.
告诉我你们还有
多少人在船上?
Tell me,how many more of you are onboard?
只要我打一枪...
It only takes one.
我看出来你已经进食过了
你的再生能力现在是最高的
I see that you've just fed,which means that your regeneration powers are at their highest,
但是我不相信
你能长出新的头来
but I seriously doubt you can grow a new head.
你要怎么样?
What do you want?
首先 你得把击昏枪给我
First,you're going to hand me the stunner.
慢慢地
Slowly.
然后 你得把你拿走的东西还给她
Next,you're going to give back what you took.
然后 你可以离开
Then,you're going to leave.
- 离开?
- 你们是坐Dart来的 对吗?
-Leave?
-You came in a dart,right?
(我们来的时候)机舱没有人看守
The bay was unguarded.
我们降落然后上了飞船
就像进入无人之境
We landed our darts and entered unchallenged.
那么 你怎么来的就怎么回去
Well,then,you're going to leave the same way you came.
这个恒星系的第二个行星
有一个轨道星门
There's a space gate orbiting the second planet in this system.
你可能要花一点时间
但是你肯定能到达
It may take you a while,but you'll get there.
如果我让她复原 就没有东西
可以阻止你食言或者杀我
If I restore her,there's nothing to stop you from going back on your word and killing me anyway.
没错
That's true.
我说有一半的机会
我会因为纯粹的仇恨而杀了你
I'd say there's a 50-50 chance I'll do it out of pure spite,
但是如果你不照做
我肯定会杀了你
but if you don't,I will kill you.
起来
Get up.
转个身
Turn around.
你没事吧?
You all right?
我不知道
I don't know.
那太奇怪了
That was so strange.
你的整个...
To have your...
生命危在旦夕
然后突然转圜了
whole life fading away,and then to suddenly have it back again.
事实上 这感觉很好
It actually felt kind of good.
我知道
I know.
在我身上发生过一次
Happened to me once,too.
说起来很复杂
Long story.
你起得来吗?
Think you can get up?
可以
Yeah.
放松...
easy...
我没事 没事
I'm okay.I'm all right.
你救了我的命
You saved my life.
第二次
Again.
如果不是你想出这个计划
我们就已经死了
If you hadn't come up with the plan,we'd both be dead.
那么你是说我们会是很好的搭档?
So are you saying we make a good team?
别发神经了
Well,don't go crazy.
好的 但是为了...
Right,but in the interest of...
星际间的关系考虑
我想我们至少...
interstellar relations,I think we should at least just...
应该试着和平共处 对吗?
try to get along,right?
你一定是在看完笑吧
You've got to be kidding me.
对不起
Sorry.
Larrin
Larrin...
对不起 Sheppard
sorry about this,sheppard,
你救了我的命 我真的很感激
and I really am grateful that you saved my life.
但是你用了一种
很奇怪的方法来表示
Well,you've got a funny way of showing it.
不要和我玩这个
Don't play hurt with me.
当你觉得你占上风的时候
你很容易变得很慷慨
It's easy to be generous when you think you have the upper hand.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
你我都知道你没有在第一时间
就把我击昏然后关起来
We both know the only reason you didn't stun me and lock me up the first opportunity you got was
是因为你以为你的船会先到达
because you thought your ships were going to get here first.
但是你错了
You were wrong about that,by the way.
Larrin 见到你真是太高兴了
Larrin,it's good to see you again.
相信我 我也是这么觉得
Believe me,I feel the same way.
你怎么找到我们的?
How did you find us?
在你们进入超空间之前
我们都在监控通讯
Well,we were monitoring communications before you jumped into hyperspace.
你知道他截走了飞船?
You knew he took the ship?
这个很明显
It seemed fairly obvious.
我们猜他的首要目标
是联系他的人
We guessed his priority would be to contact his people,
所以我们向我们原先位置附近
所有的星门发送了探测器
so we sent probes to all the space gates in the vicinity of our previous position.
终于 我们检测到了你的能量标记
Eventually,we detected your energy signature.
干得好
Well done.
现在 我要你派一些技术人员
来帮助我重启超空间引擎
Now,I want you to send over a couple of technicians to help me get the hyperdrive back online.
哦 还要一个保安队
Oh,and a security team as well.
马上就好
Right away.
哦 求你
Oh,come on.
好了 足够进行完全传感器扫描了
All right,close enough to do a full sensor sweep.
看上去有四艘船
Looks like we got four ships,
一艘是Lantian设计 Aurora级的
one of them lantian design.Aurora class.
另外三艘呢?
What about the other three?
我认不出这配置
I don't recognize the configurations.
Sheppard 在哪?
What about sheppard?
符合逻辑的假设是
他在发射信号的船上
Well,the logical assumption is that he's onboard the ship that transmitted the signal.
那是哪一艘呢?
And which one is that?
我不知道
Well,I have no idea.
我们就要进入火力范围了 博士
We're about to enter weapons range,doc.
我们瞄准哪一艘船?
Which ships do I target?
也许在攻击之前
我们应该试试通讯
Perhaps we should attempt to communicate before we attack.
我们对这些人一无所知
We know nothing about these people.
没事 但是现在
That's true,but right now,
我们唯一有的优势是
我们是隐形的
about the only thing we got working for us is the fact that we're cloaked.
如果发射信号 我们就会暴露位置
We send a signal,we give up our position.
他说的没错
He's right.
他们可能攻击我们
或者跳回超空间
They could target us,or for that matter,they could just jump back into hyperspace.
我们就前功尽弃了
We'd be right back at square one.
我们不能走了这么远却一无所获
We didn't come all this way for nothing,right?
好吧 我来看看我能不能
找到方法阻止他们离开
All right,well,I'll see if I can figure out a way to disable them.
你肯定很乐意知道
超空间引擎已经修复了
I thought you'd be glad to know the hyperdrive repairs are almost complete.
那么 祝贺你们
Well,congratulations.
你们得到了你们要得东西
You got what you want.
是的 我们可以飞行和导航
Yes,it's true I can fly the ship and navigate,
但是还有不少系统我不能访问
but there are still dozens of systems I don't have access to,
还有 如果任何一个控制器关闭了
就会有点麻烦
and if any of the controls went down,it would be a problem.
那么 完善那个适配器吧
So finish the adapter.
你说过你可以对已经初始化的
系统进行反向工程
You've said you can reverse-engineer the systems that were already initialized.
是的 我们最终会的
Well,yes,we can,eventually,
但是如果我把你留在船上
事情会快很多
but it would go a lot faster if I keep you onboard.
你是一个xx 你知道吗?
You are a piece of work,you know that?
我知道你不同意我的策略
Look,I know you don't agree with my tactics,
但是对于船的用途我说得是实话
but I wasn't lying about why I need this ship.
我是为我的人民而这么做的
I'm doing this for my people.
听着
Look...
我知道你觉得你在帮助你的人民
但是你错了
I know you think you're helping your people,but you're wrong.
什么?
Excuse me?
你们已经躲躲藏藏好几千年了
You've been running and hiding for thousands of years.
你们能活下来很好
You've survived,good for you,
但是现在你们的收益开始减小了
(Sheppard经济学的真好 还知道diminishing returns)
but now you're starting to see diminishing returns.
一艘船 能给你们多一点时间
One more ship,that buys you a little more time,but ultimately,
但是它最终不能改变什么
it's not going to change anything.
你的人民正在走向死亡
Your people are headed for a slow death.
我们还有什么选择呢?
What other choice do we have?
如果你还没听说
那你很快就会知道
In case you haven't heard,you will soon enough
Wraith正在受到攻击
,but the wraith are under attack.
被谁?
From who?
说来话长 但是他们损失惨重
It's a long story,but the point is,they're taking heavy damage,
即使他们没有被铲除
他们也会变得禁不起一击
and if they don't get wiped out,they're going to be vulnerable.
你们的人现在有超空间引擎
先进的武器 还有鬼知道什么东西
Now,you people have hyperdrives and advanced weapons,and god knows what else.
时间适当的时候
你们需要一种技术来达到平衡
When the time is right, a kind of technology to take the blance.
你是建议我们结盟吗?
Are you suggesting an alliance?
我没有邀请你吃晚餐 但是类似的
Well,I'm not asking you to dinner,but yeah,something like that.
在我让你承受了这么多以后?
After all I put you through?
就像你说的 你是为了你的人民
Well,like you said,you did it for your people.
我终究是理解错了你
I may have misjudged you after all.
好吧 博士 我们在火力范围内了
All right,doc,we're in weapons range.
我们有什么方案?
What do you got for me?
我们可以瞄准Lantian飞船的引擎
We can target the lantian ship's engines.
其他几艘怎么办?
What about the others?
我已经检查过传感器数据
但是其中的未知处太多了
I've been going over the sensor data,but there's still too many unknowns.
如果我们打错了地方
I mean,if we hit them in the wrong spot,
我们可能把他们给炸飞
也有可能Drone只能从护盾上弹过
we could blow them out of the sky,or the drones could just bounce harmlessly off the shields.
我们没有办法知道
there is no way to know
好吧 我们还有最好的选择
All right,well,it's still our best option.
我们不能让他们跑走
We can't risk them getting away.
他们走了
They're gone.
我检测到了东西
I'm getting a contact.
是一艘Jumper
It's a jumper.
一个生命信号
One life sign.
Sheppard中校 我是Loren少校
Colonel sheppard,this is major lorne.
是你吗?
Is that you?
是的 少校
That's affirmative,major.
很高兴听见你的声音
It's good to hear from you.
我也是 长官
Likewise,sir.
看起来我们差点失去你
Seemed like we came pretty close to losing you there.
你不会知道是怎么回事的
You don't know the half of it.
太好吃了
that's good.
真的?
Really?
当你跟一群宇宙流浪者呆久了
You spend enough time with a bunch of space nomads,
你就会开始珍惜你有的东西
you really begin to appreciate what you have.
很难想象把一生
都花在船上是什么感觉
It's difficult to imagine spending one's entire life onboard a ship.
如果是我的话 我会疯的
If it was me,I'd go crazy.
那么我们就是最正常的人
They weren't exactly the most even-keeled people.
我仍然不太确定
他们为什么让我走
I'm still not exactly sure why they let me go.
你向他们提出结盟
Well,you did offer them an alliance.
那肯定值点什么
That has to be worth something.
或者他们发现
你带来的麻烦比你的价值还多
Or they figured out you'd be more trouble than you're worth.
这是一个可能
That is a possibility.
不 你肯定还有什么没告诉我们
No,there's something you're not telling us.
她很性感 是不是?
She was hot,wasn't she?
我不知道你在讲什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
哦 我知道了 这太典型了
Oh,I knew it.That is so typical.
她打了我 Rodney
She had me beat,rodney.
她几次威胁要杀了我
She threatened to kill me several times.
这不是我们一起消遣去SPA那种
It wasn't like we were hanging out in the spa together.
不管怎样 我知道的是我每次被抓
Whatever.All I know is that every time I get taken captive,
都是Wraith干的
it's the wraith.
我就想被一个
性感的外星人抓住一次
Just once I would like to be taken prisoner by the sexy alien.
你可能还有机会
Well,you may still get a chance.
你什么意思?
What do you mean?
她还在宇宙之中呢
She's still out there.